radiopublic.com 2019-03-30

# RadioPublic Privacy Policy – RadioPublic

**RadioPublic Privacy Policy**

See also: [RadioPublic Terms of Service](https://about.radiopublic.com/radiopublic-terms-of-service-aeee2c4d56c5#.uodrfd5n2)  
See also: [RadioPublic Paid Listens Program Terms](https://medium.com/@jakeshapiro/radiopublic-paid-listens-program-terms-95a4c55b824d)

**Effective Date: September 1, 2016**

We take privacy very seriously at RadioPublic. It is embedded in our [mission as a Public Benefit Corporation](https://about.radiopublic.com/welcome-to-radiopublic-62745019d63#.2fv43dcsz): “We are committed to operating a platform that fairly values creators’ work, **respects users’ privacy and information rights** , and benefits all participants.” Our goal is to do more than we have to by law — we want to earn your trust that we are careful with your data.

**General information**

This policy sets out our privacy practices and explains how we handle the information we collect when you visit and use our sites, services, mobile applications, products, and content (“Services”).

**What we may collect**

We collect information about what RadioPublic pages you access, information about your mobile device (such as device or browser type), information you send us (such as an email address used to register or communicate with us), and referral information.

When you use RadioPublic Services, we may collect and store your Internet Protocol address. We may use this information to fight spam and other abuse; or to generate aggregate, non-identifying information about how people use RadioPublic Services.

**Email from RadioPublic**

Sometimes we’ll send administrative emails about account or service changes, or new policies. You can’t opt out of them. You can always opt out of non-administrative emails such as daily digests.

We won’t email you to ask for your password or other account information. If you receive such an email, send it to us so we can investigate.

**Disclosure of your information**

As a rule, we don’t share your personal information outside the company.

We won’t sell your personal information.

We may share your personal information with third parties in limited circumstances, including: (1) with your consent, or (2) when we have a good faith belief it is required by law, such as pursuant to a subpoena or other legal process.

If we’re going to share your information in response to legal process, we’ll give you advance notice so you can challenge it (for example by seeking court intervention), unless we’re prohibited from doing so by law or court order. We will object to requests for information about users of our site that we believe to be improper.

If we merge with another company such that your information will become subject to a different privacy policy, we’ll notify you before the transfer. You can opt out of the new policy by deleting your account during the notice period.

**Cookies**

We use cookies and similar technologies such as pixels and local storage to recognize you when you return to our Services. We use them in various ways, for example to log you in, remember your preferences (such as default language), evaluate email effectiveness, show relevant ads, and personalize information.

We respect Do Not Track (“DNT”) settings in browsers. If you’re logged out of our Services and have DNT enabled, we will not set cookies. By logging in you are opting to allow RadioPublic to ignore the DNT setting and to use cookies in order to provide you a personalized experience.

Some third-party services that we use, such as Google Analytics, may place their own cookies in your browser. This Privacy Policy covers use of cookies by RadioPublic only and not the use of cookies by third parties.

**Data Storage**

RadioPublic uses third-party vendors and hosting partners, such as Amazon, for hardware, software, networking, storage, and related technology we need to run RadioPublic. We maintain two types of logs: server logs and event logs.

**Modifying your personal information or deleting your account**

Use of RadioPublic does **not** require having an account.

If you do have a RadioPublic account, you can access and modify your personal information, or delete your account in your settings on RadioPublic’s mobile apps.

To protect information from accidental or malicious destruction, we may not immediately delete residual copies from our active servers and may not remove information from our backup systems.

If you delete your account, your account and content may be unrecoverable.

**Data security**

We use encryption (HTTPS/TLS) to protect data transmitted to and from our site. However, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure, so we can’t guarantee security. You use the Service at your own risk, and you’re responsible for taking reasonable measures to secure your account (like using a strong password).

**Changes to this Policy**

RadioPublic may periodically update this Policy. We’ll notify you about significant changes to it. The most current version of the policy will always be here and we will archive former versions of the policy here.

**Questions**

We welcome questions, concerns, and feedback about this policy at legal@radiopublic.com.

## Published by Jake Shapiro

Co-founder of 3 ventures @radiopublic @prx @mattervc and 3 kids! Fellow @ashoka, @BKCHarvard #zebrasunite [ View all posts by Jake Shapiro ](https://about.radiopublic.com/author/jakeshapiro/)

**Published** November 8, 2016August 16, 2018
